hey guys welcome to concept and coding
and this is Shan and today I'm going to
share the road map of spring boot with
you guys and these are all the topics
which I have come up with based on my
experience and I have covered
microservices also in that right spring
boot microservices using spring boot
they are lot of topics and yeah we will
go through one by one but yes after lldd
hld and Java this is the next playlist
I'm going to work on okay so one thing
before I tell you the topics which I'm
uh planning to cover the prerequisite is
Java like spring boot as you know it's a
kind of a Java framework like if you
don't know Java then I would say that
first go through the Java playlist and
then come back to this uh top topics
okay so first is Introduction to Spring
boot like in this part where I would be
telling like why the spring boot is
required what problem it solves what are
its features advantages so at least we
will get an introductory like okay we
are going to use a spring but why what
problem it does
solve then we will set up a basic spring
boot project and I will also try to
cover the layered architecture of spring
boot
after that I have put like understanding
of may1 pom.xml or gdel right because
this is very much we are going lot of
dependencies we are going to add if you
don't know either grel or Mayan then I
think it's better I will pick either
Mayan or grel and at least I'll cover
the structure of XML file once Mayan
pom.xml
then spring boot annotation so these are
most of the annotations which we use dat
today and based on my 8 to 9 years of
experience in total spring boot Java
spring boot these are the most common
annotations which we use right there can
be others also that's why I put asra
right so we will start with this if any
other important uh annotation is left we
will also add
it then we will understand about the
dependency injections and be
we will also cover the spring boot data
access like where it connect to the
database right so we will also cover
this part we will create a rest apis
with a spring boot right we will also
cover the spring boot security
authentication and authorization so I
have kept this
part then logging part I have kept like
uh during when we create a project we
have to do lot of loggings right so
spring boot also provide that
functionality so how to use it so that's
one of the
topic exception handling we have already
seen exception handling in Java right so
how in Spring boot we do it that's also
one of the good topic to cover spring
boot caching another very important like
at theate enable caching there are
certain annotations with this right so
you will find enable caching so there
are certain very important topics right
this is also important topic which we
will cover
Interceptor we use a lot many companies
use a lot Interceptor right so generally
Interceptor is like pre-work whatever
the task you want to perform and if you
want certain pre-work and postwork after
that task then Interceptor comes into
the picture spring boot provides a way
to add the
Interceptor a spring boot schedule eding
if you want to schedule a particular
task how to do that we have we can do
that easily using a springboard uh so I
think I can tell you uh scheduling much
more in depth because I have created a
very good project into the scheduling
part then spring boot unit testing so I
have pick mockito so we will cover with
the moito spring boot unit
testing now microservices topics with
springboard in your company you might be
using this
or maybe some internal tools but the
concept would be same okay so what are
I'm planning to cover which is which I
think is important is first thing is
Introduction to microservices so one
should understand what is
microservices right so we will discuss
about
microservices second part service
Discovery using urea so what is this
urea microservice registering so this is
the very important part you know right
each microservices there can be multiple
instances right and let's say let's say
this is microservices one there are 100
instances and this is your application
this is your application you want to
connect to this micros service now which
instance to
connect right that is what helps a
service Discovery using Ura so each
microservice registering happen very
important piece we will cover
another is tracing so what generally
happen is you have microservices
one microservices 2 microservices 3 and
then say request comes here then it goes
here then it goes here so let's say
there are so many microservices and
request goes through multiple
microservices so what does happen is
that we have to trace but let's say if
any issue comes here so right so how to
trace this request so that's where this
slith and Zipkin helps so what does
happen it the SLE will attach the trace
ID with the request so it will provide
certain Trace ID 1 2 3 4 five something
right so wherever the microsof goes
wherever the logging they will do the
logging it will go against this Trace ID
and Zipkin would provide you help you to
visualize
the microservices level logging using
this Trace ID so it's again a very
important part but just wanted to tell
you what this tracing the request means
what we have written
here then another is a spring boot
profile so what generally happen is uh
you might be working right so you want
different properties of QA production
sandbox right so that's called profiling
we have different QA environment
production environment sandbox
environment so and sometime in the code
also you have to say that okay if it is
a QA environment do this so that's that
is known as spring boot profil profiles
so we will see that
also spring Cloud config server so it's
a configuration management so what
generally happen is let's say you have
three microservices microservices 1
microservices 2 microservices 3 each
microservices has their application do
properties application. properties
application. properties so here it can
store the config but for this micros
service it can store a config but for
this but what cloud configs is that we
can have
one component where we can have a config
but that is common for all the
microservices that's why it is known as
centralized config server also but yeah
this is also something sometimes is
required so that's why I've kept it here
under the microservices part
communication between different
microservices sync and a sync where I
have put the messaging services so how
to set up a Kafka and using a spring
boot so that's where we will like if two
microservices have to communicate with
each other how they can do API gateways
right so we will write uh rest apis
right so API Gateway you can say that
the centralized server where all the
request comes and from there it will
goes to a different
microservices
right circuit breaker again important
let's say that you have microservices
one you are connected to microservices 2
let's say if this microservices 2 is
down and you keep on calling calling
calling right so sometimes your
requirement is that okay if this is down
then handle this
okay so that is can be done through
circuit
breaker so circuit breaker can be open
circuit breaker can a circuit uh breaker
can be closed right if it is closed it
goes to a fallback model okay so this is
also important all companies I can tell
you this is using right cqrs again an
important and spring boot helps to
implement this command query
responsibility segregation where the
write queries and the read queries can
be
different right so very important
part and the last which I have kept is
the deployment and
containerization right whatever the
project we're going to build how to
create an executable jar out of it how
to deploy it to a Docker container so
that will be under your microservices
topics which I can think of and finally
we will will build a project any small
project but currently in my top of head
the project which I'm thinking would be
something related to coupons but maybe
let's see that but first we understand
this topics and then we'll create a
project of it okay so this is all the
topics which I have written and just
this is just a heads up that these are
the initial topics which I have come up
with based on my experience so I might
update this list as when required uh if
I missed anything I will add it and if I
see that if something is duplicate or
not required I might update
it so this is the spring boot uh
covering from totally Basics and also
all lot of advanced topics are also
there in that if you think that if I
have missed anything please uh ping me
in the comment section and I will see
that if I can add it into what sequence
and if it is really important thank you
thank you team bye